# Nguyen Trung Hieu – Front-End Developer

(+84) 945023429 - nthieu1332002@gmail.com - 13/03/2002 https://github.com/nthieu1332002/ - https://nthieu-portfolio.vercel.app/

# Summary

With over a year of experience in modern Software Development, I specialize in:

- Web application development using ReactJS, NextJS, Javascript & Typescript.
- Mobile application development using React Native.

I am hard-working and have a keen interest in exploring as well as learning new technologies.

I am well-versed in project management tools, including Github, Gitlab, Bitbucket, Jira. My expertise also extends to optimizing performance and SEO.

### **Technical Skills**

- Web development: ReactJS, NextJS, Javascript & Typescript, HTML & CSS, SCSS, Tailwind, Redux, Zustand, Recoil, Axios, React Query, RTK Query.
- Mobile development: React Native, Android.

**Other skills:** Git, Firebase, Socket.io, Pusher, Cloundinary, NodeJs, ExpressJs, Redis, Prisma, Material UI, Ant Design, Shadcn UI, ChartJs, Rechart, Framer Motion, npm/pnpm...

# **Professional Experience**

### AIARA Corporation (Korea) – Junior Front-End Developer (Remote)

11/2023 - Now

- Collaborated with other team members to complete UI and implement functionalities for both website and mobile sections.
- Managed and maintained over 60 web and mobile pages, including graphics and online marketing materials, ensuring optimal functionality and visual appeal.
- Developed fully reusable code to streamline future projects and enhance efficiency.
- Implemented effective SEO strategies.

#### R2S Corporation (Vietnam) – Intern Front-End Developer

08/2022 - 01/2023

**Project:** ITJobs (9 members, 5 frontends, 4 backends)

- **Description:** A recruiment web application that focus on IT jobs, supply dream jobs for jobseekers and help recruitors find their suitable employees.
- Technologies:
  - o Frontend: ReactJS, Javascript, Redux toolkit, SCSS & Material UI.
  - Backend: Java Spring Boot with MySQL.
- Responsibilities:
  - Collaborated with other teams (BA, BE, Tester) to optimize the project solution and effective work.
  - Built main features and administrator functionalities.
  - Refactored code, fixed bugs.

### **Projects**

**Project:** Chanh Xe Mien Tay (5 members, 3 frontends, 2 backends)

08/2023 - 01/2024

**Description:** A platform (web and mobile) bridges Freight Forwarder and customers, offering flexible route search capabilities matched by the ChanhXeMienTay system. It not only enables customers to find

suitable routes but also provides Freight Forwarder with modern and user-friendly features management at an extremely affordable fee.

### • Technologies:

- o Frontend: NextJs, React Native, Typescript, Zustand, Tailwind, Ant Design.
- o Backend: PHP Laravel, AWS, Cloudinary, Google Maps API with PosgreSQL Database.

### Responsibilities:

- o Designed, built UI and implement system functions for both web and mobile app.
- o Reviewed code of other members to ensure functions quality.
- Wrote document and report to council of examiners.

# Repository:

- o Web: <a href="https://github.com/nthieu1332002/capstone-project-customer/">https://github.com/nthieu1332002/capstone-project-customer/</a>
- o Mobile: https://github.com/nthieu1332002/chanhxemientay-customer-mobile/
- **Demo:** https://chanhxemientay.vercel.app/

# Project: Discord Clone (Individual Project)

08/2023 - 09/2023

- Description: Fullstack Nextjs, Prisma application that clone Discord's features and UI.
- · Technologies:
  - o Frontend: NextJs, Typescript, Shadon UI, Zustand, Livekit.io.
  - o Backend: Nextjs, Prisma, Clerk, Tailwind, Socket.io, Pusher, Cloudinary.

#### Features:

- Authentication with Google, Github.
- o Realtime messages, online users with Pusher and Socket.io.
- Video call, voice call with Livekit.io.
- Repository: https://github.com/nthieu1332002/discord-clone/
- Demo: https://chanhxemientay.vercel.app/

**Project:** IMIU (5 members, 2 frontends, 3 backends)

03/2023 - 06/2023

- **Description:** Application about Food/Cooking, supply recipes, nutrition, how to cook.
- Technologies:
  - o Frontend: ReacJS, SCSS, Redux Toolkit, RTK Query, Ant Design, Firebase, React-Chart.
  - Backend: ASP.NET with MySQL Database.
- **Responsibilities:** Leader take the main responsibility in team, manage team's work progress, making design & database decisions, features, requirements, Ul... And implement features's application.
- Repository: https://github.com/LeNPhu/imiu-web/
- Demo: <a href="https://imiu-web.vercel.app/">https://imiu-web.vercel.app/</a>

#### **Project:** Safe Building (5 members)

01/2023 - 03/2023

- **Description:** Website for apartment management. Allows admins to manage all information about statistics, data, systems, users, contracts...
- **Technologies:** ReactJS, TypeScript, SCSS, Redux Toolkit, Ant Design, Firebase, Recharts...
- Responsibilities:
  - Leader to take the main responsibility in the team, manage the team's work progress, plan the design of the database, features, requirements, UI...
  - Set up and build the base code for the web team.
- Repository: <a href="https://github.com/nthieu1332002/Safe-Building-Web-TS-Vite/">https://github.com/nthieu1332002/Safe-Building-Web-TS-Vite/</a>
- Demo: https://safe-building-web.vercel.app/

### Education

FPT University | 12/2020 - 01/2024 Major: Software Engineering

# For More Information, Please Check Out My Portfolio, Github & Facebook

Portfolio: https://nthieu-portfolio.vercel.app/ Github: https://github.com/nthieu1332002/

Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/MediumHealing13/